${\color{red}\boxtimes}~CHUANXIA001@e.ntu.edu.sg$

• lyndonzheng

Homepage: https://chuanxiaz.com/

Chuanxia Zheng

Research Interests

My research centers on computer vision and machine learning. I am interested in creating a photorealistic virtual world. I have done a wide range of research on 2D image generation, completion and translation, 3D scene reconstruction, translation and interpretation.

Education

Ph.D. in Computer Science, SCSE Thesis: Synthesizing Photorealistic Images with Deep Generative Learning	2017.08-2021.06
Advisor: Tat-Jen Cham and Jianfei Cai Beihang University MA.E. in Automation Science Thesis: Context-based Indoor Scene Understanding for Mobile Robot Advisor: Jianhua Wang and Weihai Chen	2014.09–2017.03
	2010.09–2014.07
Employment	
Monash University Research Fellow at Monash Research Institute of Science and Technology Research interests: 2D image generation and 3D generation	2021.08-2022.08
Huawei Research Research assistant at Noah's Ark Lab Research interests: face recognition and generation	2017.01–2017.06
	2016.05–2016.09
Awards & Honors	
NTU Outstanding PhD Thesis Award	2022
TMM Outstanding Reviewer Award	2021
NTU Research Scholarship	2017
First Prize Scholarship for Excellent Student	2015,2016
Outstanding Graduate of Beijing	2014
National Second Prize of the National Electronic Design Contest of China (Best one in Be	e ijing) 2013
Hanergy Scholarship Award (Top 1 %)	2012
Siemens Scholarship Award (Top 1%)	2011
Press Coverage	
NTU News: NTU SCSE Outstanding PhD Thesis Award 2022	2022
Zhuanzhi: How to create photo-realistic images? Ph.D. Thesis from Dr. Zheng	2022
Sohu: AgileGAN — a new tool for creating stylized portraits	2021

Research Experience

VinAI , The national AI research Lab of Vietnam, Vietnam, Prof. Hung Bui Cooperator on high quality image generation and data compression two papers submitted to NeurIPS	2021.11-2022.08
Department of Data Science & AI, Monash University, Australia, Prof. Jianfei cai	2021.08 – 2022.08
Research interests: nature scene generation and completion	
three papers accepted by $CVPR(1)$, $ECCV(2)$, one paper submitted to $TPAMI$	
Mechanobiology Institue (MBI), NUS, Singapore, Prof. Lim Chwee Teck	2020.01 - 2021.10
Cooperator on cell nuclear generation	
one paper submitted to Nature	
Institute for Media Innovation (IMI), NTU, Singapore, Prof. Nadia Thalmann	2017.08 – 2021.06
Research interests: photorealistic image generation	
seven papers accepted by CVPR(2), ECCV(1), ICCV(1), SIGGRAPH(1) and IJCV(2)	
IR&MCT Lab, Beihang University, China, Prof. Weihai Chen	2014.09 – 2017.03
Research interests: secne understanding and segmentation	

Publications CVPR(3), ECCV(3), ICCV(1), IJCV(2), SIGGRAPH(1)

- [16] Jyothsna Vasudevan*, **Chuanxia Zheng***, James G. Wan, Tat-Jen Cham, Lim Chwee Teck, and Javier G. Fernandez. From qualitative data to correlation using deep generative networks: Demonstrating the relation of nuclear position with the arrangement of actin filaments. *PloS one*, 17(7):e0271056, 2022.
- [15] Qianyi Wu, Xian Liu, Yuedong Chen, Kejie Li, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Jianfei Cai, and Jianming Zheng. Object-compositional neural implicit surfaces. In *Proceedings of the European Conference on Computer Vision* (*ECCV*), 2022.
- [14] Yuedong Chen, Qianyi Wu, Chuanxia Zheng, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. Sem2nerf: Converting single-view semantic masks to neural radiance fields. In Proceedings of the European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), 2022.
- [13] Chuanxia Zheng, Tat-Jen Cham, Jianfei Cai, and Dinh Phung. Bridging global context interactions for high-fidelity image completion. In Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition(CVPR), pages 11512–11522, June 2022.
- [12] Chuanxia Zheng, Duy-Son Dao, Guoxian Song, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. Visiting the invisible: Layer-by-layer completed scene decomposition. *International Journal of Computer Vision (IJCV)*, 129(12):3195–3215, 2021.
- [11] Yujun Cai, Yiwei Wang, Yiheng Zhu, Tat-Jen Cham, Jianfei Cai, Junsong Yuan, Jun Liu, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Sijie Yan, Henghui Ding, Xiaohui Shen, Ding Liu, and Nadia Magnenat Thalmann. A unified 3d human motion synthesis model via conditional variational auto-encoder. In *Proceedings of the International Conference on Computer Vision(ICCV)*, pages 11645–11655, 2021.
- [10] Chuanxia Zheng, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. Pluralistic free-form image completion. International Journal of Computer Vision (IJCV), 129(10):2786–2805, 2021.
- [9] Guoxian Song, Linjie Luo, Jing Liu, Wan-Chun Ma, Chunpong Lai, **Chuanxia Zheng**, and Tat-Jen Cham. Agilegan: stylizing portraits by inversion-consistent transfer learning. *ACM Transactions on Graphics* (*TOG*), 40(4):1–13, 2021.
- [8] Chuanxia Zheng, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. The spatially-correlative loss for various image translation tasks. In Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition(CVPR), pages 16407–16417, 2021.
- [7] Chuanxia Zheng, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. Pluralistic image completion. In *Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)*, pages 1438–1447, 2019.
- [6] Tianyi Zhang, Jingyi Yang, Chuanxia Zheng, Guosheng Lin, Jianfei Cai, and Alex C Kot. Task-in-all domain adaptation for semantic segmentation. In 2019 IEEE Visual Communications and Image Processing (VCIP), pages 1–4. IEEE, 2019.

- [5] Chuanxia Zheng, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. T2net: Synthetic-to-realistic translation for solving single-image depth estimation tasks. In Proceedings of the European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), pages 767–783, 2018.
- [4] **Chuanxia Zheng**, Jianhua Wang, Weihai Chen, and Xingming Wu. Multi-class indoor semantic segmentation with deep structured model. *The Visual Computer (TVCJ)*, 34(5):735–747, 2018.
- [3] Jianhua Wang, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Weihai Chen, and Xingming Wu. Learning aggregated features and optimizing model for semantic labeling. *The Visual Computer* (**TVCJ**), 33(12):1587–1600, 2017.
- [2] Chuanxia Zheng, Jianhua Wang, Weihai Chen, and Xingming Wu. Semantic segmentation based on aggregated features and contextual information. In 2016 IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Biomimetics (ROBIO), pages 862–867. IEEE, 2016.
- [1] Jianhua Wang, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Weihai Chen, and Xingming Wu. Learning contextual information for indoor semantic segmentation. In 2016 IEEE 11th Conference on Industrial Electronics and Applications (ICIEA), pages 1639–1644. IEEE, 2016.

Preprints

- [4] **Chuanxia Zheng**, Long Tung Vuong, Jianfei Cai, and Dinh Phung. Movq: Modulating quantized vectors for high-fidelity image generation. *Under reviewer of NeurIPS*.
- [3] Long Tung Vuong, Trung Le, He Zhao, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Mehrtash Harandi, Jianfei Cai, and Dinh Phung. Wasserstein vector quantization auto-encoder. *Under reviewer of NeurIPS*.
- [2] Yuzhu Ji, **Chuanxia Zheng**, and Tat-Jen Cham. One-shot human motion transfer via occlusion-robust flow prediction and neural texturing. *Under reviewer*.
- [1] **Chuanxia Zheng**, Guoxian Song, Tat-Jen Cham, Jianfei Cai, Linjie Luo, and Dinh Phung. High-quality pluralistic image completion via code sharing. *arXiv*.

Academic Services

Journal Reviewer	
IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence	TPAMI
International Journal of Computer Vision	IJCV
IEEE Transactions on Image Processing	TIP
IEEE Transactions on Multimedia (Outstanding Reviewer Award, 2021)	TMM
IEEE Transactions on Circuits and Systems for Video Technology	TCSVT
Computer Vision and Image Understanding	CVIU
The Visual Computer	TVCJ
Neural Computing and Applications	NCAA
Conference Reviewer.	
ICLR	2023
CVPR, ECCV, ICLR, NeurIPS, SIGGRAPH, SIGGRAPH Asia, IJCAI, ACM MM, IROS	2022
CVPR, ICCV, ICLR, ACM MM	2021
CVPR, ECCV	2020
ICCV	2019
Talks	
Synthesizing Photorealsitic Scenes, SCSE Gratuate Chat Series Discussion, NTU	2022.09
Synthesizing Photorealsitic Scenes, Computer Vision & Geometry Group, ETH	2022.06
Synthesizing Photorealsitic Scenes, Graphics & Geometric Computing Laboratory, USTC	2022.01

Pluralistic Image Completion, Institute of Media Innovation, NTU	2019.11
Depth Estimation from Single 2D Image, Institute of Media Innovation, NTU	2018.06
Teaching	
Teaching Assistant, Advanced Digital Image Processing, Graduate, NTU	2018-2020
Teaching Assistant, Human-Computer Interaction, Undergraduate, NTU	2018 – 2020
Teaching Assistant, Engineering Mathematics, Undergraduate, NTU	2018 – 2019